Mohd Sadiq

Cambridge, Cambridgeshire, United Kingdom

■ +447767975520 | Mary mohdsadiq8998@gmail.com | Degithub.com/ms2892 | Degithub.com/in/mohd-sadiq-cam

Personal Profile

Specialist in Machine Learning with 2+ years of experience and a **Masters Degree from University of Cambridge**, specializing in MLOps and Deploying Machine learning models in the field of Computer Vision and Reinforcement Learning (PyTorch and Tensorflow) using cloud based technologies like AWS. Looking to advance career in Machine Learning, Data Scientice and Software Engineer positions.

Major Achievements

- Re-architectured and optimized an image clustering pipeline for clustering of scenes in a movie that reduced the processing time by 84
- Developed a novel split based algorithm to improve solution time in retrosynthesis using Microsoft's Syntheseus.
- Developed a Ticket grading feature using an ensemble of large models.
- · Authored and published 2 research papers.

Tech Stack

Python, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Docker, NumPy, Scikit-learn, OpenCV, Git, AWS (Batch, S3, ECR, EC2), Metaflow, Nvidia (Triton, TLT Kit), MatplotLib, Seaborn, C++, ReactJS, HTML/CSS, Flask, SQL

Work Experience __

Ryff Cambridge, UK

Machine Learning Engineer

May 2023 - Current

- Overhauled and optimized an existing image clustering pipeline that reduced the processing time by 84%.
- · Architectured a pipeline to use Recognize Anything Model and DINOv2 to increase the number of objects detected in an object by 60 times.
- Founded a novel pipeline to estimate voxels around a given object in a given scene using Segment Anything Model, VoxelNext and Depth estimation using 1 image
- Deployed end to end models on K8s and AWS Batch using Metaflow for 75% of the existing workflows
- Spearheaded in standardizing the Logging system for all modules.
- Modularized the prevailing video processing pipeline with a bespoke architecture with 60% faster processing.

Volunteer Cambridge, UK

Front End Web Developer

February 2023 - May 2023

• Revamped UI design for UniArk (Deployed at: https://uniark.org/) which 93% of stakeholders preferred.

RBCDSAI, IIT Madras Chennai, India

Project Associate

September 2021 - August 2022

- Designed a novel human in the loop learning algorithm that helped in reducing the human biases in datasets that had an improvement of 5% on the benchmark datasets.
- Spearheaded and collaborated 5 machine learning projects for stakeholders that revolved around reinforcement and supervised learning.

Wobot AI New Delhi, India

Computer Vision Engineer

May 2021 - September 2021

- Developed a Ticket grading feature for the clients to judge the authenticity of a false positive.
- Implemented bespoke models or pipelines for different use cases using Pytorch, Tensorflow and ONNX over Triton servers with average model
 processing time of 120 milliseconds.

Jamia Millia IslamiaNew Delhi, India

Research Student

June 2020 - September 2022

- Authored and published 2 research papers in reputed journals like Springer IJFS and TSP CMC (First Author).
- Guided a team of skilled individuals in research projects and published 1 paper in field of Computer Vision.

MixOrg New Delhi, India

Internship November 2020 - January 2021

- Conducted research on use of AI to improve the success rate of embryo transfer in IVF for humans (15% improvement in accuracy).
- · Created a synthetic image generation application using StyleGAN to enhance the existing dataset (10% difference in accuracies).
- Developed a Heat map generation model for inferences learnt by the model using Grad CAM (63% of stakeholders preferred the product with this feature).

September 24, 2023 1

Education

University of Cambridge

Cambridge, UK

MPhil in Machine Learning and Machine Intelligence

Result Awaited

Jamia Millia Islamia

New Delhi, India

October 2022 - August 2023

BTech in Computer Engineering

CPI: 9.16/10 First Division with Honours

August 2017 - August 2021

Thesis

Nearest Neighbor Value Function For Chemical Retro Synthesis

Cambridge, UK

University of Cambridge

May 2023 - August 2023

- Researched a split based heuristic of molecule to estimate the cost of synthesizing the molecule.
- Developed a Reinforcement Learning model to learn to split the molecule up based on 3 reward functions.
- Improved cost estimation (value function) quantified by time taken for first solution.
- Implemented the value function in Microsoft Syntheseus

Publications

JOURNAL ARTICLES

Attention-Based Deep Learning Model for Early Detection of Parkinson's Disease

Mohd Sadiq, Mohd Tauheed Khan, Sarfaraz Masood

Tech Science Press-Computers, Materials Continua 71.3 (Dec. 2022) pp. 5183–5200. 2022

FD-YOLOv5: A Fuzzy Image Enhancement Based Robust Object Detection Model for Safety Helmet Detection Mohd Sadiq, Sarfaraz Masood, Om Pal

International Journal of Fuzzy Systems 24.5 (Apr. 2022) pp. 2600–2616. 2022

CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS

SCS-Net: An efficient and practical approach towards Face Mask Detection

Umar Masud, Momin Siddiqui, Mohd Sadiq, Sarfaraz Masood

Procedia Computer Science 218 (Jan. 2023) pp. 1878-1887. 2023

Interests_

Cooking I host weekly cooking session with a group of friends with various cuisines

Front End Design In my free time I sometimes like to implement certain web designs/elements using HTML and CSS only.

Writing

I am writing a collection of short stories that I wish to publish one day

Badminton

I go to badminton sessions in sport centres on a bi-weekly basis

Travelling I love travelling and have a bucket list of countries that I wish to cross off.

Languages

English Professional proficiency **Hindi** Native proficiency

September 24, 2023 2